Finding Aid for Law School (University of Michigan) oral history interviews, 1988-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Law School (University of Michigan) oral history interviews
1988-2002
University of Michigan--Law School.
9762 Bimu 2
The Law School History Oral History Interviews contain transcripts and audio cassette tapes of interviews with University of Michigan Law School faculty discussing their background, education, careers, and the Law School.
1.7 linear feet
126 audiocassettes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Received from the University of Michigan Law School in various accessions (Donor No. 343 ).
University records are public records and once fully processed are generally open to research use. Records that contain personally identifiable information will be restricted to protect individual privacy. The restriction of university records is subject to compliance with applicable laws.
The following are terms of restriction for specific genres of records found in this record group:
Interview transcripts in the Law School Oral History Project record group without signed consent forms on file are considered restricted. Transcripts for which no signed consent form is on file are noted in the inventory.
In 1988 an oral history project was launched by the University of Michigan Law School to interview retired and emeritus faculty members. In some instances the spouses of deceased faculty members were interviewed. The interviews were conducted by Enid H. Galler. Typed transcripts of the interviews were made from the taped interviews and an index to subjects covered on each tape was created.
This record group consists of three series, Oral History Transcripts, Oral History Audiocassettes, and Oral History Computer Discs. The series contain audiocassettes, bound copies of the transcripts and subject indexes, and a small number of computer discs with transcript files. Transcripts and cassettes are arranged alphabetically by interviewee.
The interviews typically include discussions of the interviewees' backgrounds and education, and subsequent commentary on legal education. The administration of the law school is well covered in these interviews which also add significant detail to the operation of the University as a whole.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Law School.Law School.; Oral histories.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; Allen, Francis Alfred, 1919-; Baker, Oscar W.; Brown, Elizabeth Gaspar, 1913-; Chambers, David L., 1911-; Conard, Alfred F. (Alfred Fletcher), 1911-2009; Cooperrider, Luke K.; Estep, Samuel D.; Gray, Whitmore.; Joiner, Charles Wycliffe, 1916-; Kamisar, Yale.; Kennedy, Frank R.; Leidy, Paul Allen B., 1888-; Leidy, Kathryn.; McCree, Dores.; Palmer, George E.; Pierce, William J.; Proffitt, Roy Franklin, 1918-; Reed, John Wesley, 1918-; Sandalow, Terrance, 1934-; Smith, Allan Frederick, 1911-; Smith, Russell Andrew.; Stein, Eric.; Steiner, Peter Otto, 1922-; Watson, Andrew.; Browder, Olin L.; Israel, Jerold H., 1934-; St. Antoine, Theodore J., 1929-; Pooley, Beverly J.; Galler, Enid.
- Oral History Transcripts
  - Allen, Francis A., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Oscar W., 1995 (Box 1)
  - Browder, Orin L. Jr., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Elizabeth G., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Chambers David L., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Conard, Alfred F., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Cooperrider, Luke K., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Estep, Samuel D., 1993 (Box 1)
  - Gray, Whitmore, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Israel, Jerold, 1997 (Box 1)
    (Restricted: signed release form absent)
  - Joiner, Charles W., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Kennedy, Frank R., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Kamisar, Yale, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Leidy, Kathryn (Mrs. Paul Leidy), 1992 (Box 1)
  - McCree, Dores (Mrs. Wade McCree), 1996 (Box 1)
  - Palmer, George E., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Pierce, William J., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Pooley, Beverley J., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Profitt, Roy F., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Reed, John W., 1990 (Box 1)
  - St. Antoine, Theodore J., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Sandalow, Terrance, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Smith, Allan F., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Smith, Russell A., 1989 (Box 2)
  - Stein, Eric, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Steiner, Peter O, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Watson, Andrew G., 1993 (Box 2)
- Oral History Audiocassettes
  Transcripts to Oral History Audiocassettes are located in the Oral History Transcripts series.
  - Allen, Francis A., 1990 (Box 3)
  - Baker, Oscar W., 1995; 2 audiocassettes (Box 3)
  - Browder, Orin L. Jr., 1989; 2 audiocassettes (Box 3)
  - Brown, Elizabeth G., 1989; 3 audiocassettes (Box 3)
  - Chambers, David L., 2002; 6 audiocassettes (Box 3)
  - Conard, Alfred F., 1989; 5 audiocassettes (Box 3)
  - Cooperrider, Luke K., 1991; 3 audiocassettes (Box 3)
  - Estep, Samuel D., 1993; 8 audiocassettes (Box 3)
  - Gray, Whitmore, 1995-1996; 4 audiocassettes (Box 3)
  - Israel, Jerold, 1997; 5 audiocassettes (Box 4)
  - Joiner, Charles W., 1991; 6 audiocassettes (Box 4)
  - Kamisar, Yale, 2000-2001; 9 audiocassettes (Box 4)
  - Kennedy, Frank R., 1989; 4 audiocassettes (Box 4)
  - Leidy, Kathryn (Mrs. Paul Leidy), 1992; 1 audiocassettes (Box 4)
  - McCree, Dores (Mrs. Wade McCree), 1996; 3 audiocassettes (Box 4)
  - Palmer, George E., 1988; 3 audiocassettes (Box 4)
  - Pierce, William J., 1990; 5 audiocassettes (Box 4)
  - Pooley, Beverley, 1997; 7 audiocassettes (Box 4)
  - Profitt, Roy F., 1989; 5 audiocassettes (Box 5)
  - Reed, John W., 1990; 4 audiocassettes (Box 5)
  - Sandalow, Terrance, 10 audiocassettes (Box 5)
  - St. Antoine, Theodore, 1998; 9 audiocassettes (Box 5)
  - Smith, Allan F., 1988; 3 audiocassettes (Box 5)
  - Smith, Russell A., 1989; 3 audiocassettes (Box 5)
  - Stein, Eric, 1989; 4 audiocassettes (Box 5)
  - Steiner, Peter O, 1994; 3 audiocassettes (Box 5)
  - Watson, Andrew G., 1993; 5 audiocassettes (Box 5)
- Oral History Computer Discs
  - 5 1/4" Discs
    - Browder, Olin L. (Box 5)
    - Brown, Elizabeth G. (Box 5)
    - Kennedy, Frank R. (Box 5)
    - Proffitt, Roy F. (Box 5)
    - Smith, Allan F. (Box 5)
  - 3 1/2" Discs
    - Allen Frances A. (Box 5)
    - Stein, Eric (Box 5)